<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Slowerzs&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://slowerzs.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Slowerzs&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 22:13:55 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://slowerzs.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FCSC 2021 - Reporter</title>
      <link>https://slowerzs.github.io/post/fcsc-reporter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 22:13:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slowerzs.github.io/post/fcsc-reporter/</guid>
      <description>Reporter  Vous arrivez dans une nouvelle entreprise qui utilise un navigateur conçu en interne. Pouvez-vous obtenir un shell sur la machine de la personne qui vérifie les liens qu&amp;rsquo;on lui envoie ?
  http://challenges2.france-cybersecurity-challenge.fr:4009/
 For this challenge, we are given a binary, named fcsc_browser, and a link, where we can submit urls. With the description of the challenge and the category, we expect this challenge to be a browser exploitation challenge : the goal is to craft a malicious website, that upon visit with the fcsc_browser, will trigger arbitrary commands and execute a reverse shell, allowing us to gain access to the machine of the bot visiting the links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FCSC 2021 - Blind Date</title>
      <link>https://slowerzs.github.io/post/fcsc-blind-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 21:43:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slowerzs.github.io/post/fcsc-blind-date/</guid>
      <description>Presentation I&amp;rsquo;m Nathan Blondel, a 20 years old CTF player, currently student at Telecom SudParis. I go by the alias of Slowerzs. This is my second participation, and though I couldn&amp;rsquo;t spend as much time as I wished, I still enjoyed the competition !
Blind Date This challenge was part of the Pwn category, and was worth 500 points. Given the challenge name, and the fact that no binary is given, we expect this challenge to be some sort of blind rop challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
